Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we're
going shopping for something. What are we
going shopping for Marco? That's right.
Today we are buying pants and we're gonna
try to see if we find a good pair of jeans.
Yeah, sometimes pants are too small.
Sometimes they're too big.
Let's try and find the right pair today.
Excuse me. Can I try on this pair of jeans?
Sure. Let me see. I'm afraid we don't have
any sides, eight's left.
What are you talking about?
I'm always a size
four. Here, I'll try
these. They seem a bit too tight. Shall I
find you a larger size? No, they fit fine.
They show off my cuz perfectly. Yeah,
your love handles. They sure do. Although
here you forgot to close this button. Yeah
right. I'll do it now. All right, we're
back. So now let's take a look at some
vocab on language takeaway. Language take
away. All right, so today on language
takeaway, the first phrase we have is
actually a verbal phrase. This is what
we do when we go to find some clothes.
We try on those
clothes. That's right.
So that is a as you said,
a verbal phrase and to try
on a pair of pants or
to try on some clothes.
It's to put them on
and see if they are okay
if they're the right
size. That's right.
So if I'm in the store and
I see a shirt that I really
like, I go to the
dressing room to try it on
or you could say, oh my
gosh, Marco, come here.
The shirt is great.
You should try it on.
That's right. So you try it
on or you try on something.
All right. So as we said,
we wanted to try on
a pair of jeans. So
let's take a look at this
connection of words.
Pair of jeans. All right.
So you don't have a jeans.
You have a pair of them.
And this is because you
have not one, but two legs.
So pair means two of something.
That's right. So it doesn't
mean that you have two pants.
Right. It doesn't mean that you have two
pieces of clothing. It means that you have
one piece of clothing
that's a pair of jeans.
That's right. So you have one part for
one leg and one part for another leg.
The same is true of glasses because,
you know, glasses are for your two eyes.
That's right. You
have a pair of glasses.
That's right. A pair of
glasses, a pair of shoes.
Also, okay. So we are
trying on these pair of
jeans, but they seem
to be a bit too tight.
All right. So tight is where we
use when something is too small.
It's hard to move
if something is
too tight. So maybe if the
pants are too small, they
might be too tight. Yeah.
And we often say this,
especially to girls. My
mom used to say this, oh
no, you're not wearing
that skirt. It's too tight.
You can see or you can
see your body underneath.
Okay. So actually the opposite would
be loose if something's too big. Too big.
If it's too big, it's loose.
If it's too small, it's tight.
Okay. Now if it's not
too big and not too small,
then that means it
fits. It fits. That's right.
So I could say, I think I want to
buy this pair of jeans. It fits very well.
So if the pants or
the pair of jeans fit, it
means they are okay for you.
They're not too big, not too small.
They're comfortable,
comfortable.
And in this case, she said that they fit
perfectly because they show off her curves.
Now, what is she talking
about? My curves. Well, a curve is
something that's
not straight. It bends.
But when we're talking
about a person's curves,
we're talking about
maybe a woman's hips or
her behind her rear
end or her chest. And so
women who have curves
maybe are rounder, not flat.
Okay. So it's something
that usually you would
use with the girls, right,
that a girl has nice curves.
You wouldn't really say
that for a guy, I think.
No, guys, you don't
really talk about curves.
But with girls, usually
you can see someone's
curves if she wears
tight clothes. Okay.
Very good. So why
don't we take a break?
Let's review all this vocab and we'll
be back in a bit with fluency builder.
Excuse me. Can I try on this pair of jeans?
Sure. Let me see.
I'm afraid we don't
have any size eight's left.
What are you talking
about? I'm always a size four.
Here, I'll try these.
They see what bit tube tight.
Shall I find you a larger size?
No, they fit fine. They show off my
curves perfectly. Yeah, your love handles.
They sure do. Although
here, you forgot to
close this button.
Yeah, right. I'll do it now.
All right. Now it's
time for three phrases.
Let's take a look at
those on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
All right. So we heard
this phrase here, I'm afraid.
And it means something
may be different
from what you've heard
before. So the shopkeeper
said, I'm afraid we don't
have any size eight's left.
That's right. So when
you start a sentence
like this, you're basically
apologizing a little bit, right?
Yeah, it's like
saying, I'm sorry.
I don't think we
have size eight's left.
So maybe I go into
the store and I say, well,
I would like some
chocolate milk please.
And I say, I'm sorry, I'm afraid
we ran out of chocolate milk.
I'm afraid we ran out.
So this means it's too bad or
unfortunately, we don't have any.
That's right. So it's not the same being
afraid like you're being, you're scared.
No, it's not that afraid.
It's a polite way for
usually a shopkeeper to say,
I'm sorry, we can't help you.
Okay. So going back to curves,
the girl used this interesting
phrasal verb there to show off.
All right. So we know the word to show,
but to show something off, to show off,
means to display or
exhibit. It's almost like
you're, you want other
people to look at you.
Okay. So if I guess maybe
you can see it on the
street, if someone is
in their car and they're
playing loud music,
kind of drawing attention
to their car, they're kind
of showing off their car.
They want you to see
their car or just hear
how great sound system
they have. That's right.
Or some women will
wear very, very short skirts
because they want to
show off their long legs.
That's right. All right.
But now something that
you don't really want to
show off are your love handles.
All right. Now this is
a very funny phrase.
It's actually something
we say in spoken
English that if you say to
someone else might be very rude.
Love handles are
the part of your body
above your waist that
if you have a little fat,
it's like, it's like they're
squishy. You can touch them.
Right. So just think
about how maybe people
that are a little bit
overweight, they put on
a pair of pants and on
their sides and their waist,
the extra skin that kind
of is around the pants,
that's called love
handles. And we say love
handles because when
someone hugs you or they
want to hold you, that's
where they put their
hands, there's extra to
hold on. I think sometimes
they're even called, they
may be called like tires
or something like this.
Well, spare tires in the front.
It's near your belly. All right.
So that's called a spare tire.
That's right. So a spare tire
is in the front. It's a belly
normally when people
drink a lot of beer very
often. They have a spare
tire, but this is actually
love handles are on the sides.
But that's our last word today.
Let's remember that it's not
something you want to go
around telling people
they have, but you can joke
with your friends.
Right. Exactly. All right.
So let's listen to the
dialogue one last time.
Excuse me. Can I try on this pair of jeans?
Sure. Let me see.
I'm afraid we don't have any sides,
eight's left. What are you talking about?
I'm always a size four.
Here. I'll try these.
They see a bit too tight.
Shall I find you a larger size?
No, they fit fine. They show off my
cuts perfectly. Yeah, your love handles.
They sure do. Although
here you forgot to
close this button.
Yeah, right. I'll do it now.
All right. So speaking
about pants, I've noticed
something that the girl asked for
size four, but she really was a size eight.
So how does this work? Because
as guys, we don't have size
fours, five or ones or
anything. We like you buy
a pair of jeans. You
say size 32 and the waist
and size 30 and length
or something like this.
So that's right. Men's
clothes usually indicate the
size of your waist. So
32 is a 32 inch waist.
But women's clothes don't
have those measurements.
And I sometimes think
it would be better if we
did because it's very
hard. Some stores have
size four, which is one
size, but if you go to
another store, it's very
different. So you always
have to try on these
clothes. But normally in
America, the sizes go
from zero, which is the very,
very smallest to 14 or
16, which is the largest.
Okay. Normal size for most
women would be an eight,
I think an eight or 10.
And now obviously this
depends on the countries,
because like for example,
being in Asia in China,
the women are usually a
little bit thinner or
smaller. So it's harder,
I think for, it's harder
to actually have
this universal form of
measurements for girls.
That's right. So in the
back of your pants, for
example, they'll usually
be some fabric and it will
say the size according
to different countries.
So in America, size six in
China, size, I don't know,
28. And so they'll have the different
numbers and UK is also different size.
Kind of like your
shoes. If you look inside
your shoe, it'll say, I
think a Japanese size,
the UK size, which is like 41, 42. And the
USA size, which is like size eight or nine.
So it's very, very
interesting, especially when
you're buying clothes,
you have to remember
what size you are and
you have to ask the person
to that you try it on
because some things I know
you can't try on,
right? That's right.
And in some stores, you have
to ask for help to take things
off the racks so it
can be very difficult.
But normally, if you
say, hey, can I try this on,
the shopkeeper will help
you? Okay. Great stuff.
And of course, if you
have any questions or you
want to comment on
this lesson or any of our
lessons, you can find
us at EnglishPod.com.
We hope to see you all there.
All right. Bye. Bye.